https://www.bushchurchaid.com.au/privacy

Log in  /  Checkout  /  Items in cart
Toggle navigation
DONATE
Who We Are Our VisionHow We ServeOur PartnersOur BoardNational Redress SchemeOur PeopleGet Involved ServePrayDonateDistance Giving ProgramLeaving a BequestBCA for KidsCurrent VacanciesResources Current PublicationsThe Real Australian ArchiveReconciliation Action PlanPolicies & Other ResourcesDrought/Disaster ReliefBCA VideosNews Latest NewsEventsShop Donate
Privacy Statement
THE BUSH CHURCH AID SOCIETY OF AUSTRALIA PRIVACY STATEMENT
The Bush Church Aid Society of Australia respects your privacy. We are bound by the Australian Privacy Principles set out in the Privacy Amendment (enhancing Privacy Protection) Act 2012. The Bush Church Aid Society of Australia provides Christian missionary care in remote areas of Australia, together with medical care and religious instruction in schools.
The information we collect
BCA collects personal information such as your name, age, contact details, occupation, church details, payment details and financial information. We use this information so we can receive and receipt donations and maintain communication with our supporters. We will also use this information to communicate with you the needs of BCA and the news from our Field Staff. In the case of volunteers or BCA Nomads we may collect additional personal information which is deemed necessary for one or more of our functions or activities. When we collect sensitive information (as defined in Act) we will collect it with your consent, unless the law allows us to collect it without your consent.
Financial information
If you make a donation via our website we will request your name, contact and credit card details. These details will only be used for the single donation unless you request otherwise. BCA is PCI compliant (Payment Card Industry) and your credit card and bank account details are encrypted.
How we collect and hold your information
Personal information is collected directly from you, either by your completion of an application form, a donation form, a deputation sign-up sheet or online.
BCA consistently reviews the security of its data.
• It is held in a secure work environment and secure password protected databases ensure your personal information is secure from misuse, loss or unauthorised use or disclosure.
• Firewalls and virus scanning tools are used to ensure our server is secure.
• BCA is PCI compliant and your credit card and bank account details are encrypted.
• Access to your information is constantly monitored by management to ensure that only those who need to see your personal information do so.
Disclosure of information
BCA may share your personal information amongst associated entities but only insofar as it relates to the primary reason BCA collected your information.
BCA may disclose your personal information to third party service providers such as mailing houses or contractors from time to time to help us to provide our services to you. If we do this, mailing houses or contractors are forbidden to use the information supplied to them other than for the purposes as set out by us.
BCA will only disclose personal information to others if you have given us permission to do so, or if the disclosure relates to the main reason we collected the information and you would reasonably expect us to do so.
BCA will not disclose your information to overseas recipients.
Links to other websites
Whilst the Society contains links to third party websites, we are not responsible for the privacy practices of those sites.
Access to personal information
Generally, you have a right to access personal information we hold about you. If we deny your request in some circumstances we will tell you why. You may also
• seek the correction of your personal information
• request not to receive further information from BCA
• have a complaint about our breach of the Australian Privacy Principles
In such cases please contact:
The Bush Church Aid Society of AustraliaPrivacy Compliance OfficerGreg BridgeLevel 7, 37 York Street, Sydney, NSW 2000Phone +61 2 9262 5017Email Greg Bridge
Who We Are Our Vision
How We Serve
Our Partners
Our Board
Our People
BCA for Kids
Who We Are Our Vision
How We Serve
Donate BCA is a not for profit organisation. We rely on the donations of our faithful supporters.
Donate BCA is a not for profit organisation. We rely on the donations of our faithful supporters.
Contact Us We have offices in each state and territory. We'd love to hear from you.
Contact Us We have offices in each state and territory. We'd love to hear from you.
© 2020 The Bush Church Aid Society of Australia  /  Privacy Statement  /  Disclaimer  /  Professional Standards
